David Stamm

whylom@gmail.com github.com/whylom linkedin.com/in/whylom twitter.com/davidstamm

I've been hacking on code for startups, agencies, and nonprofits for over 15 years. And I still find great joy in teaching and learning from my colleagues, expressing complex truths in simple code, and helping my team get faster & happier every day.

Skills

I use these every day in my current position

Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Grape, RSpec, Sidekiq, JS, CoffeeScript, jQuery, AWS, Heroku, Redis, PostgreSQL, nginx, Vagrant, Git, Bash

I have used these at some point over the last 15 years

Java, C++, PHP, Perl, ASP, ColdFusion, Oracle, MySQL, SQL Server, memcached, Beanstalkd, Sphinx, HAProxy, Chef, Engine Yard, XSLT, XPath, Subversion

Recent Experience

General Assembly

generalassemb.ly

New York, NY

Tech Lead, Infrastructure 10/2015 - present

- Asked to build an elite team to maintain the organization's most critical systems, I made Infrastructure into the most fun, supportive, fearless, and innovative team at GA.
- Designed and built a REST API for GA's aging Rails monolith.
- Built a Ruby framework for creating API clients with a simple ActiveRecord-like interface.
- Built and maintained internal Heroku buildpacks to customize application environments.
- Built a robust API to process 100% of marketing leads from every part of the organization.
- Modernized the nginx server that routes traffic to the apps powering various sections of GA's website, adding tests, monitoring, and a full development environment.
- Mentored junior devs through pair programming, code review, and one-on-one discussion.

Tech Lead, Circuits 12/2014 - 10/2015

- Happily returning to a team lead role after a year in management, I helped bring camaraderie and momentum to the team supporting GA's online learning platform.
- Helped build a browser-based SQL database UI for the launch of our Data Analytics course.
- Used a simple mini-project (migrating complex email logic from a 3rd party service into our platform) to bring the team together around a shared technical vision.

David Stamm

whylom@gmail.com github.com/whylom linkedin.com/in/whylom twitter.com/davidstamm

General Assembly (cont.)

generalassemb.ly

New York, NY

Director of Engineering 2/2014 - 12/2014

- While we searched for a permanent director, I led engineering for nearly a year, helping to lay the foundations of a strong engineering culture that persists to this day.
- Led a team of 20 engineers, managed 10 direct reports, while mentoring a newly promoted engineering manager and several first-time team leads.
- Restructured engineering to pit our best team against our hardest problems, and give our most embattled team some easy wins.
- Moved our entire stack to Heroku, reclaiming 100s of developer-hours per week previously lost to ops firefighting.
- Elevated remoting from a necessary evil to a core part of our culture.

Engineering Manager 9/2013 - 2/2014

- Promoted after only 6 weeks at GA, I managed the 4 engineers responsible for Front Row, GA's video subscription product.
- Took a strong team to the next level by simplifying process & automating everything.

Software Engineer 7/2013 - 9/2013

I was among the first wave of experienced devs to join a very junior team.

Previous Experience

Paperless Post

paperlesspost.com

New York, NY

Team Lead 1/2013 - 7/2013 Web Developer 5/2012 - 12/2013

Working on the startup's iconic card design interface and their very first print offering, I
learned the ins and outs of a larger engineering team operating at scale.

Canvas canvas.is New York, NY

Director of Engineering 4/2010 - 4/2012 Lead Software Engineer 2/2009 - 4/2010 Senior Web Developer 11/2008 - 2/2009

• I helped transform this innovative digital agency's engineering department into a nimble and cohesive team, and I fell in love with Ruby along the way.

David Stamm

whylom@gmail.com github.com/whylom linkedin.com/in/whylom twitter.com/davidstamm

Nylon Technology

nylontechnology.com

New York, NY

Web Developer 2/2006 - 5/2008

• It was at this small web dev shop, I started to apply what I had learned about people and process by taking the lead on some big projects.

AAMC aamc.org Washington, DC

Web Developer 8/2003 - 2/2006

 Rebooting the world's most widely used medical school application system the came with some unique challenges, like bulk scanning college transcripts.

NetStrategies

netstrategies.com

Alexandria, VA

Web Developer 12/2001 - 3/2003

 Building dynamic web sites for trade associations was pretty boring, but was also a crash course in what makes projects succeed or fail.

Akoo <u>now defunct</u> Chicago, IL

Web Developer 2/2000 - 8/2001

• Launching a streaming music portal in the years before Pandora or Spotify was the best first job I could have asked for.

Education

The College of William and Mary Williamsburg, VA Bachelor of Arts, Music Composition, September 1998

- Admitted to the James Monroe Scholar honors program.
- Completed 3 semesters of introductory computer science courses, introducing software engineering with C++ and object-oriented analysis & design.
- Studied composing and conducting, ancient Greek, and as much Western history and English literature as I could fit into my schedule.

Things I Love

reading books written for 5th graders • the age of Napoleon: Beethoven, Jane Austen, Lord Nelson • planetary science, evolutionary biology, genetics • the history of words • speedcubing • following my mad genius daughter on adventures, both real and virtual • learning new languages by getting lost in other countries • writing music and stories • debugging systems made of code (software) and people (teams) • lightning talks, karaoke, anything that lets me share my enthusiasm in public • teaching or learning just about anything